<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Rhys Bower</title>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/atom.xml"/>
  <link href="http://www.rhysbower.com/"/>
  <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/</id>
  <updated>2015-04-10T12:44:44Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rhys Bower</name>
    <email>bowerrhys@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2015 Rhys Bower.</rights>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Tech April Fools 2015</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/04/tech-april-fools-2015/"/>
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/04/tech-april-fools-2015</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Every year tech companies like to have some fun on April Fools. This is a round up of some of the best jokes from this year.</p>

<hr />

<p><a href="https://com.google">com.google</a></p>

<p>This is not a one page stunt. The entire Google Search is horizontally flipped. Definitely check this one out and be prepared to be confused.</p>

<p><a href="https://com.google"><img class="img-responsive" src="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/tech-april-fools-2015/com.google.png" alt="com.google" /></a></p>

<hr />

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=584qPWzfhHY">#MotoSelfieStick</a></p>
<div class="videoWrapper">
  <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/584qPWzfhHY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<hr />

<p><a href="http://lumiaconversations.microsoft.com/2015/04/01/microsoft-launches-ms-dos-mobile/">MS-DOS Mobile</a></p>

<p>For everyone who needs to run their childhood programs on their phone (if you were around back then).</p>

<div class="videoWrapper">
  <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/irJQDGw8Ptk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<hr />

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/TeslaMotors/status/583339439759310848">Tesla Parking Ticket Avoidance</a></p>

<p>This is exactly what we need self driving and thinking cars for.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-video" lang="en"><p>No more parking tickets for Model S owners. Today we’re introducing: ticket-avoidance-mode. Here’s how it works:&#10;<a href="https://t.co/uPFF3J5XyS">https://t.co/uPFF3J5XyS</a></p>&mdash; Tesla Motors (@TeslaMotors) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeslaMotors/status/583339439759310848">April 1, 2015</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<hr />

<p><a href="https://maps.google.com">Google Maps Pacman</a></p>

<p>I’m not sure if this beats the <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=google%20doodle%20pacman">Google Doodle Pacman</a> from a few years ago because the controls are confusing due to the odd angles of the roads.</p>

<p><a href="https://maps.google.com"><img class="img-responsive" src="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/tech-april-fools-2015/pacman.png" alt="Google Maps Pacman" /></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="text">How I fixed my over fourteen second, 31 HTTP request website.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/fixed-fourteen-second-load/"/>
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/fixed-fourteen-second-load</id>
    <published>2015-03-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p><strong>The problem with my slow site.</strong></p>

<p>When my portfolio initially went online it was hosted with <a href="http://www.heroku.com">Heroku</a> on their free tier. This was great.  It was fast and easy to deploy with <code>git</code> but only after the server warmed up.</p>

<p>I noticed that some page loads were taking over fourteen seconds and 31 HTTP requests to download all of the content for that page. Fourteen seconds! This was unacceptable and I knew that it had to be fixed fast.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/fixed-fourteen-second-load/slow-waterfall.png"><img class="img-responsive" src="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/fixed-fourteen-second-load/slow-waterfall.png" alt="Fourteen second, 31 HTTP request waterfall" /></a></p>

<p>To understand why this is we have to take a look at one of the key “features” of the Heroku free tier, server sleeping. Once a Heroku app with only one instance has been idle for an hour Heroku will sleep the server to save resources.  Unfortunately my site is not that active and I hit the one hour with no hits fairly frequently, causing my server to sleep.</p>

<p><strong>Architecting a solution.</strong></p>

<p>My initial thought was to prevent Heroku from sleeping my server. The only way to do this is to add another server. The total for adding that server came to around $34.50 per month. It’s not a bad price for two load balanced web servers but I clearly didn’t need the extra capacity that they would provide.</p>

<p>At this time the site also was powered by a Ruby with Sinatra stack. In reality this was only to power the contact forum and nothing else.</p>

<p>I wanted to add a blog to this site as explained in <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey/">Blogging My Freelance Journey</a> so I switched my site from Ruby to PHP so that I could more easily integrate WordPress into a <code>/blog</code> sub-directory. Note that I chose to make the blog the home page of the domain in the end.</p>

<p>Now I needed a MySQL database to store the WordPress content and Heroku was only going to charge me more for the most basic functionality.</p>

<p>To get around the expensive hosting I made a list of the items that I wanted from my site:</p>

<ol>
  <li>host some of my projects (or links to them as complex projects would most likely be on their own domain)</li>
  <li>host a simple, static blog as the comments could be carried out over <a href="http://www.twitter.com/BowerRhys">Twitter</a>. <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a> is also a very popular commenting system for static websites and is an option to add comments to this site in the future.</li>
</ol>

<p>It was clear that all I needed was a static site. I knew that I needed a generator to include a standard header and footer on every page. <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator and is quite popular right now. It has the added bonus of automatic compilation on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>. Although I can no longer take advantage of this because of the tag plugin I use.</p>

<p><strong>GitHub Pages to the Rescue</strong></p>

<p>Because my site was already version controlled in <a href="http://git-scm.com/">Git</a> GitHub Pages was a logical service provider for my static site (plus it’s free).</p>

<p>After moving my site to Jekyll and GitHub Pages the speed increased greatly because of two reasons:</p>

<ol>
  <li>GitHub has fast servers that don’t sleep (this is the majority of the speed up)</li>
  <li>My site no longer needed to be compiled on every page load (this is a small factor)</li>
</ol>

<p>At this point I introduced <a href="http://gulpjs.com/">Gulp</a> to build the site. With Gulp I automated concatenation of the CSS and javascript (which I wasn’t doing before) and optimized images for the web. All together I was able to reduce the number of HTTP requests from 31 to 22 and the page size from 4.2 MB to 2.7 MB.</p>

<p>I should also mention that the size of the downloaded CSS was significantly reduced due to compiling Bootstrap from source and omitting the unused components but is a small factor compared to the image optimization.</p>

<p>With these changes I finally achieved sub two second response times. Still slow but much better than where I started.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/fixed-fourteen-second-load/fast-waterfall.png"><img class="img-responsive" src="http://www.rhysbower.com/img/posts/fixed-fourteen-second-load/fast-waterfall.png" alt="Two second, 22 HTTP request waterfall" /></a></p>

<p><strong>What’s next?</strong></p>

<p>There is still work to be done but I am more comfortable with the performance now than a week ago. Some things that I am considering are minifying the HTML and inlining the Google Analytics javascript to remove the need for the additional HTTP request as the only page that requires additional javascipt is the <a href="">portfolio</a> page.</p>

<p>I have heard good things about <a href="http://www.cloudflare.com/">CloudFlare</a> and will have to check them out. It will add another layer to the stack which I don’t really want to do especially because CDNs can be unpredictable as to when they update the cache of your content.</p>

<p><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></p>

<p>Heroku is a great platform and is very easy to use however it gets very expensive very quickly. Check it out only for production apps that need to run server side code.</p>

<p>I had to make some compromises with the new site specifically with the no comments nature of a static site and restricting my ability to run server side code. Hopefully the fourteen to two second load time and 31 to 22 HTTP request reductions will justify the compromises that were made.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="text">The Importance of Building your Brand</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/importance-building-brand/"/>
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/importance-building-brand</id>
    <published>2015-03-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>To be noticed in an extremely saturated environment like web development I believe that your brand becomes very important.  It’s the reason that the site <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/">www.rhysbower.com</a> exists along with this blog.  The more people that see me as a knowledgeable person in the industry the more likely I am to gain clients.  Both my <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/portfolio/">portfolio</a> and <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com">blog</a> are designed to showcase the best of my work and convince prospective clients that I am the right person for the job.</p>

<p><strong>How to build your brand?</strong></p>

<p>1) Website</p>

<p>Your website will become your online identity.  It’s the first thing people will find when they search for you or your services (if it isn’t you need to work on SEO like me). It’s often said to “never judge a book by its cover” but rarely applied so make sure the your website is the best possible version of you. This is the reason that I am constantly iterating on the design of the site.</p>

<p>I am using <a href="http://gulpjs.com/">gulp</a> to automate most of the build process except the actual push to the live site. As my site is hosted on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> my production site is versioned through git so a simple copy of the site to the master branch followed by a <code>git push</code> gives you all of my latest changes.</p>

<p>2) Email</p>

<p>Email is still the predominant method of communication when connection with new people.  It’s the one platform that you can expect everyone to be on. Because of this you should take the time to get email setup at your domain. Currently I am still evaluating the different service providers before I make my decision.</p>

<p><strong>So what should I do?</strong></p>

<p>When you are starting out consider the little things that help you look professional. Usually they aren’t very expensive and once you have them setup you can forget about some of them. Make sure that the content at the surface of your site has a wow factor that pull your readers further into your content.</p>

<p>Ensure that you provide a way for visitors to contact you when they have found something interesting. Make sure that your communication pathways are open so that visitors can contact you in the methods that work best for them.</p>

<p>Lets hope that this advice turns out to be correct and helps me grow my site.  If you have any suggestions for me send me a tweet <a href="http://www.twitter.com/BowerRhys">@BowerRhys</a> and I’ll be sure to get back to you.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="text">Blogging my Freelance Journey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey/"/>
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey</id>
    <published>2015-03-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Hello world. It’s the phrase that all developers have probably typed many times.  The inaugural program to learn a new language.</p>

<p>I started working with computers nearly ten years ago when I was in elementary school.  I remember working with ActionScript 2 although I haven’t used it in ages. ActionScript will always hold a special place in my heart. It was the first language that I used on a client project. It was the first language that I used in my games and my websites.  But that is the past.</p>

<p>More recently I have used PHP and Ruby and have started dabbling in frameworks instead of hand coding everything. Over time I have been able to develop my skills to where I am today.</p>

<p>The past few months I have begun thinking about what I need to do differently to grow in the industry and find success in my niche. How do I get my name out there and grow my first clients? I quickly realized that while I may know something about computers I have no idea about how to start a business.</p>

<p>I also asked myself why not start a blog?  It would keep a journal of journey and push me to constantly improve. Hopefully by sharing my journey as I build my business and go to school you will find my success and failure to be an interesting story, one that captivates you, the readers, and motivates you as well as myself to improve our careers and future.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>


</feed>