<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Rhys Bower</title>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/atom.xml"/>
  <link href="http://www.rhysbower.com/"/>
  <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/</id>
  <updated>2015-03-24T07:29:14Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rhys Bower</name>
    <email>bowerrhys@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2015 Rhys Bower. All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="text">The Importance of Building your Brand</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/importance-building-brand/" />
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/importance-building-brand</id>
    <published>2015-03-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>To be noticed in an extremely saturated environment like web development I believe that your brand becomes very important.  It’s the reason that the site <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/">www.rhysbower.com</a> exits along with this blog.  The more people that see me as a knowledgeable person in the industry the more likely I am to gain clients.  Both my <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com/portfolio/">portfolio</a> and <a href="http://www.rhysbower.com">blog</a> are designed to showcase the best of my work and convince prospective clients that I am the right person for the job.</p>

<p><strong>How to build your brand?</strong></p>

<p>1) Website</p>

<p>Your website will become your online identity.  It’s the first thing people will find when they search for you or your services (if it isn’t you need to work on SEO like me). It’s often said to “never judge a book by its cover” but rarely applied so make sure the your website is the best possible version of you. This is the reason that I am constantly iterating on the design of the site.</p>

<p>I am using <a href="http://gulpjs.com/">gulp</a> to automate most of the build process except the actual push to the live site. As my site is hosted on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> my production site is versioned through git so a simple copy of the site to the master branch followed by a <code>git push</code> gives you all of my latest changes.</p>

<p>2) Email</p>

<p>Email is still the predominant method of communication when connection with new people.  It’s the one platform that you can expect everyone to be on. Because of this you should take the time to get email setup at your domain. Currently I am still evaluating the different service providers before I make my decision.</p>

<p><strong>So what should I do?</strong></p>

<p>When you are starting out consider the little things that help you look professional. Usually they aren’t very expensive and once you have them setup you can forget about some of them. Make sure that the content at the surface of your site has a wow factor that pull your readers further into your content.</p>

<p>Ensure that you provide a way for visitors to contact you when they have found something interesting. Make sure that your communication pathways are open so that visitors can contact you in the methods that work best for them.</p>

<p>Lets hope that this advice turns out to be correct and helps me grow my site.  If you have any suggestions for me send me a tweet <a href="www.rwitter.com/BowerRhys">@BowerRhys</a> and I’ll be sure to get back to you.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title type="text">Blogging my Freelance Journey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey/" />
    <id>http://www.rhysbower.com/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey</id>
    <published>2015-03-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Hello world. It’s the phrase that all developers have probably typed many times.  The inaugural program to learn a new language.</p>

<p>I started working with computers nearly ten years ago when I was in elementary school.  I remember working with ActionScript 2 although I haven’t used it in ages. ActionScript will always hold a special place in my heart. It was the first language that I used on a client project. It was the first language that I used in my games and my websites.  But that is the past.</p>

<p>More recently I have used PHP and Ruby and have started dabbling in frameworks instead of hand coding everything. Over time I have been able to develop my skills to where I am today.</p>

<p>The past few months I have begun thinking about what I need to do differently to grow in the industry and find success in my niche. How do I get my name out there and grow my first clients? I quickly realized that while I may know something about computers I have no idea about how to start a business.</p>

<p>I also asked myself why not start a blog?  It would keep a journal of journey and push me to constantly improve. Hopefully by sharing my journey as I build my business and go to school you will find my success and failure to be an interesting story, one that captivates you, the readers, and motivates you as well as myself to improve our careers and future.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>


</feed>