<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rhys Bower</title>
    <description>Rhys Bower is an aspiring local developer working on a number of personal programming projects. Rhys will be attending UBC for Computer Science next year.
</description>
    <link>http://www.rhysbower.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.rhysbower.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 13:27:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 13:27:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging my Freelance Journey</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world. It’s the phrase that all developers have probably typed many times.  The inaugural program to learn a new language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working with computers nearly ten years ago when I was in elementary school.  I remember working with ActionScript 2 although I haven’t used it in ages. ActionScript will always hold a special place in my heart. It was the first language that I used on a client project. It was the first language that I used in my games and my websites.  But that is the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently I have used PHP and Ruby and have started dabbling in frameworks instead of hand coding everything. Over time I have been able to develop my skills to where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few months I have begun thinking about what I need to do differently to grow in the industry and find success in my niche. How do I get my name out there and grow my first clients? I quickly realized that while I may know something about computers I have no idea about how to start a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also asked myself why not start a blog?  It would keep a journal of journey and push me to constantly improve. Hopefully by sharing my journey as I build my business and go to school you will find my success and failure to be an interesting story, one that captivates you, the readers, and motivates you as well as myself to improve our careers and future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.rhysbower.com/blog/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.rhysbower.com/blog/2015/03/blogging-my-freelance-journey/</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
